(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
シャカビーチ〜Laka Laka La〜
Shaka Beach ~Laka Laka La~
作詞：TAKUYA∞ / 作曲：UVERworld
Lyrics: TAKUYA∞ / Composition: UVERworld
ギラギラのBeach way
Glittering beach way
夏のHo age
Summer's sail hoisting
願ってみがってな一夏のGame
Selfish wishes, a one-summer game
Lock-on 君を待ってたんだ
Lock-on, I was waiting for you
Bad know you
ギラギラの瞳で
With glittering eyes
口説くPlayとTune
Play and tune for wooing
横切った時にガンのScope
A gun's scope as you crossed by
Lock-on 1人だけ
Lock-on, only one person
Lock-on 宇宙のセンター
Lock-on, center of the universe
あー髪に逆らってでも
Ah, even if it goes against the grain
もっとの刺激に満ちた季節を
A season filled with even more excitement
終わらせない夏が
The summer that won't let it end
今僕の心を広げてく
Is expanding my heart right now
波風 笑い声
Sea breeze, laughter
Laka Laka Love Laka Laka Love
この空 雲 虹に乗って
Riding this sky, the clouds, the rainbow
砂浜の君の足跡
Your footprints on the sandy beach
見つけるから
Because I'll find them
あー Laka Laka Love Laka Laka Love
Ah, Laka Laka Love Laka Laka Love
夜は群がってビーチ向かいのBar
At night, flocking to the bar across the beach
今宵も探す恋愛のGame
Searching for a game of love tonight too
俺がシレッとそして特攻切る
I'll nonchalantly take the lead
お前はアシストパス出せ OK?
You give me the assist pass, okay?
行こうか夜の同志達よ
Shall we go, comrades of the night?
企みだらけのただれた関係
A relationship full of schemes and decadence
Lock-on 当たって砕けろ
Lock-on, go for broke
Lock-on 狩り初めの月に惑わされ
Lock-on, bewitched by the hunting moon
事情なんかより先に行動
Action before explanations
近づく唇がドギツイハバネロ言語
Approaching lips, intense Habanero language
それも悪くない夏が
That's not bad either, the summer
今僕の心を広げてく
Is expanding my heart right now
波風 笑い声
Sea breeze, laughter
Laka Laka Love Laka Laka Love
この空 雲 虹に乗って
Riding this sky, the clouds, the rainbow
高い山見下ろして
Looking down from a high mountain
耳澄ましたら
If I listen closely
あー Laka Laka Love Laka Laka Love
Ah, Laka Laka Love Laka Laka Love
ロンリー ロンリー あいに揺らぎ出てきたけど
Lonely lonely, though I came out wavering in love
ロンリー ロンリー 心の中は Nobody knows
Lonely lonely, inside my heart nobody knows
答えは波の調べ
The answer is in the melody of the waves
探す足跡 消えてゆく前に
Before the footprints I'm looking for disappear
君の光の色が広げていく
The color of your light is expanding
波風 笑い声
Sea breeze, laughter
Laka Laka Love Laka Laka Love
この空 雲 虹に乗って
Riding this sky, the clouds, the rainbow
砂浜の君の足跡
Your footprints on the sandy beach
見つけるから
Because I'll find them
夏が今君と僕を...
Summer now takes you and me...
引き寄せられる 地団駄は痛いよ
I'm being drawn in, my frustrated stomping hurts
Laka Laka Love Laka Laka 海よ
Laka Laka Love, Laka Laka, Oh Ocean
春も秋も冬も 飲み干してゆけ
Drink up spring, autumn, and winter too
まだまだ終わらせない この夏は
I won't let this summer end just yet
あー Laka Laka Love Laka Laka Love
Ah, Laka Laka Love, Laka Laka Love
Lonely Lonely 目には見えないその愛は
Lonely, lonely, that invisible love is...
Lonely 今のままじゃ 見つけられないんだよ
Lonely, I won't be able to find it as I am now
Lonely Lonely 心に嘘をついても
Lonely, lonely, even if I lie to my heart
あーーーーー！
Aaaaaaaah!
あ、あれ？あれみんな聞いてたのー？
Oh, wait. Wait, everyone was listening?
あーこんまっするー！
Ah, Konmassuru!
ホロライブ三期生の白銀ノエルです！
I'm Shirogane Noel from hololive 3rd generation!
イェーイ！見てるー？
Yay! Are you watching?
今日は団長の100万人記念の3Dライブにお越しいただきありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming to my 1 million subscriber
commemoration 3D live today!
やっぱね、1曲目といったらこの曲でしょ。
As I thought, for the first song, it has to be this.
ちょっとまだ夏は来てないけど、シャカビーチ歌わせていただきました！
Summer hasn't quite arrived yet,
but I sang 'Shaka Beach'!
イェーイ！
Yay!
いやー、ね、しかもね。
Yeah, and also...
あの、ハッシュタグもあるのでね。
We also have a hashtag.
えっと...あ、こっちだ、こっち。
Let's see... ah, over here, over here.
あの「#白銀ノエル100万人記念3Dライブ」で、
Using #白銀ノエル100万人記念3Dライブ...
いっぱい写真を撮ったり、あの、感想を呟いたりして、
Please take lots of photos and tweet
your impressions...
目指せ、トレンド！
Aim for the trends!
まぁ、三位くらい入れたらいいな、ということで、
It'd be nice if we could hit top 3 or so...
よろしくお願いします！イェーイ！
So please do! Yay!
あちあち、なんかもうね。
Hot, hot... it's like...
夏だね。
It's summer, isn't it?
なんか全然さ、なんか六月って感じしなく...
It doesn't feel like June at all...
あーめっちゃ暑いんですけど。
Ugh, it's really hot.
まあ、この暑さに負けないシャカビーチだったんじゃないかなと思います。
Well, I think that 'Shaka Beach' performance
could hold its own against this heat.
ちょっと団長のこのサングラス姿もいっぱい撮ってください。ピチピチ。
Please take lots of photos of me in
these sunglasses too! *camera sounds*
まあねシャカビーチ、ちょっと普段、まあ歌枠とかで歌ってるんだけど、
I usually sing 'Shaka Beach' in karaoke streams,
やっぱ3Dってなるとこう、動きがつくから。
But in 3D, you add movement to it.
あの団長いつもね、こう...
I always move my hands like this even in 2D,
「地団駄は痛いよ、Laka Laka Love」って、手は動いてるんだけど、実は。
But singing with my whole body...
でもやっぱこうやって全身で歌うのは、あー、ちょっと大変だなぁと思いました。
Well, I realized it's quite hard work.
いや、本当にみんなもまだまだね、これからライブ、続きますんで。
The live will continue, so...
ちょっと団長の勇姿を見ててくださーい。
Please keep watching my heroic efforts!
もしかしたらこの、この...まあいつもの衣装じゃなく、
Maybe I'll change from this usual outfit...
まあお馴染みのあの衣装にも、
To that familiar one soon,
着替えるかもしれないんで、今のうちにこの写真、撮っておいてください。
So take photos of this while you can!
ピョ。ピョ。
Pyo. Pyo.
あ、最近うっしーになったから。もう、もう...
Oh, I became a cow recently... Moo, moo...
牛さんだと、あ、待って！
As a cow... wait, look!
見てみんな、ほら！
Look everyone, look!
やっぱビーチだからさ、沈む。地団駄は痛いよ。
Since it's a beach, I'm sinking.
My frustrated stomping hurts!
見て、ほら！
Look, look!
団長と...いや、本当はね、これで水着だったら良かったんだけど、
Me and... honestly, it would have been great
if I was in a swimsuit,
ちょっとね、YouTube君が興奮しちゃうから、ちょっと団長水着ないんだよ。
But YouTube-kun would get too excited,
so I don't have a swimsuit.
でもみんなの心の目でね、団長を水着にしてください。
But please see me in a swimsuit
with your mind's eye!
見てるー？
Are you watching?
いやーいいね、これ、あー。
Ah, this is nice...
あーびしゃびしゃ、びしゃびしゃ。
Ah, I'm soaking wet!
見て、この水の感じが。冷たいな、水。ちょうどいいわ。
Look at this water effect. The water is cold.
It feels just right.
いやなんかさ、このねビーチ、この団長ね選んだ理由があるんだけど、
There's a reason I chose this beach stage.
あのここSSSでね、あの先輩方が、その水着でわーって歌ってて、
My seniors sang SSS in swimsuits here.
ちょうど団長、三期生がデビューする前だったから、憧れてたんだけど、
It was before the 3rd gen debuted,
so I really looked up to them.
あの、まあなんかね、そん時には3Dもなく、まあ水着もなく、って感じで...
At that time I didn't have 3D or a swimsuit...
いやでも団長もこうやってSSSではないが、こう先輩たちのビーチで歌えて、ハッピーハッピーです！
But now I'm singing at my seniors' beach.
I'm so happy!
キチチュチュ。
Kichichuchu.
すごいね、こんな感じで水が。はい！団長キャッハッハッハ。
The water is like this... Yay! *Noel sounds*
っていう感じで、ちょっと一人だと寂しいなー。
But being all alone like this is a bit lonely.
なんか寂しい...
It's kind of lonely...
団長、ちょっと一人でね、前から言ってるけど、一人でソロライブってなんかちょっと辛い。ライブするの辛いから、なんと！
A solo live all by yourself is a bit tough.
So!
これから先、ちょっと素敵なゲストをお呼びしているので、
I've invited some wonderful guests!
そちらに...そちらもよろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to them too!
いや、誰かな、誰かな、ワクワク。
Who could it be? I'm so excited!
ということで、移動しようと思います。
With that, I'm going to move locations.
いやーみんな楽しみにしててねー。
Everyone, look forward to it!
バイバーイ！またねー！
Bye bye! See you later!
皆様、本日はお忙しい中、
Everyone, thank you for taking the time
多数ご参加くださいまして、誠にありがとうございます。
to join us today despite your busy schedules.
まずは皆様方のご健康を祝して...
First, to celebrate the health of all of you...
乾杯！
Cheers!
酒が飲める 酒が飲める 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink sake, we can drink sake, yeah!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲める
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
1月は正月で酒が飲めるぞ
In January, it's New Year's, so we can drink sake!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
2月は豆まきで酒が飲めるぞ
In February, it's bean-throwing, so we can drink sake!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
3月はひな祭りで酒が飲めるぞ
In March, it's the Doll Festival, so we can drink sake!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
4月はお花見で酒が飲めるぞ
In April, it's cherry blossom viewing, so we can drink sake!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
5月は子供の日で酒が飲めるぞ
In May, it's Children's Day, so we can drink sake!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
6月は田植えで酒が飲めるぞ
In June, it's rice planting, so we can drink sake!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
7月は七夕で酒が飲めるぞ
In July, it's Tanabata, so we can drink sake!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
8月は暑いから酒が飲めるぞ
In August, it's hot, so we can drink sake!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
9月は台風で酒が飲めるぞ
In September, it's typhoons, so we can drink sake!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
10月は運動会で酒が飲めるぞ
In October, it's the sports festival, so we can drink sake!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
11月は何でもないけど酒が飲めるぞ
In November, there's nothing special, but we can drink sake!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
12月はどさくさで酒が飲めるぞ
In December, it's the year-end rush, so we can drink sake!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
よし、それでは続いて、日本全国飲み歩いて行こう！まずは北海道から！
Alright, next let's go drinking all over Japan! Starting with Hokkaido!
北海道は毛ガニで酒が飲めんでないかい
In Hokkaido, we can drink sake with hair crab, can't we?
酒が飲める 飲めんでないかい 酒が飲めんでないかい
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink, can't we?
秋田はきりたんぽで酒が飲めるぞ
In Akita, we can drink sake with kiritanpo!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
山形はさくらんぼで酒が飲めんだの
In Yamagata, we can drink sake with cherries!
酒が飲める 飲めんだの 酒が飲めんだの
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink, yeah!
茨城は納豆で酒が飲めっぺよ
In Ibaraki, we can drink sake with natto!
酒が飲めっぺ 酒が飲めっぺ 酒が飲めっぺよ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink, yeah!
静岡はお茶と一緒に酒が飲めるづら
In Shizuoka, we can drink sake along with tea!
酒が飲める 飲めるづら 酒が飲めるづら
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink, yeah!
京都は舞妓はんと酒が飲めるどす
In Kyoto, we can drink sake with maiko-san!
酒が飲める 飲めるどす 酒が飲めるどすえ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink, yeah!
富山は越中ふんどしで酒が飲めるぞ
In Toyama, we can drink sake in Ecchu loincloths!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
岡山はきびだんごで酒が飲めるぞな
In Okayama, we can drink sake with kibi-dango!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞな 酒が飲めるぞな
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink, yeah!
愛媛は伊予柑で酒が飲めるでねー
In Ehime, we can drink sake with Iyokan oranges!
酒が飲める 飲めるでねー 酒が飲めるでねー
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink, yeah!
長崎はカステラで酒が飲めばってん
In Nagasaki, we can drink sake with Castella cake!
酒が飲める 飲めばってん 酒が飲めるばってん
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink, yeah!
鹿児島は西郷隆盛と酒が飲めるとよ
In Kagoshima, we can drink sake with Saigo Takamori!
酒が飲める 飲めるとよ 酒が飲めるとね
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink, yeah!
沖縄は行ったことないけど酒が飲めるぞ
I've never been to Okinawa, but we can drink sake there!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
日本全国どこへ行っても酒が飲めるぞ
No matter where you go in Japan, you can drink sake!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
酒が飲める 酒が飲める 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink sake, we can drink sake, yeah!
酒が飲める 飲めるぞ 酒が飲めるぞ
We can drink, we can drink, we can drink sake!
あ、起きるとするか。
Ah, let's wake up then.
起きた、飲んだ。おはようございます。
I woke up, I drank. Good morning.
よいしょ... 頭が...
Heave-ho... My head...
頭痛いな...
My head hurts...
はーい！
Haaa-i!
本当に、お二人さん、来てください、ありがとうございます。
Truly, the two of you, thank you for coming today.
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
いっぱい乾杯してね。お酒飲んだから...
Have lots of toasts with me. Since I'm drinking...
乾杯！
Cheers!
乾杯！ でっか！
Cheers! It's huge!
飲んでるけどね。
I'm drinking, but...
リスナーさんもみんな知ってると思うんですけど
I think all the listeners already know, but...
この三人、知ってますか？ なんでこの三人なのか。
Do you know these three? Why these three?
わかりますか？
Do you know?
なんと我ら、ホロ酒飲み組！
We are the Holo Sake-Drinking Group!
イエーイ！
Yay!
今初めてやった。ちょっといきなり...
That was the first time I did that.
ぶっ込んでしまった。
I just threw that in there.
なので、団長のやっぱこのホロ酒飲み組でやりたいことっていったら
So, what I really wanted to do as this Holo Sake-Drinking Group...
やっぱこの有名な、お酒の歌をね、歌って親睦をさらに深めたいなと思って。
...was to sing this famous sake song to deepen our bond.
本当に来てくれてありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for coming.
ありがとうございます！ よかった、こうやって。
Thank you! I'm glad we could do this.
ホロライブ屈指の酒好きさんたちだからね。
We're the top sake lovers in Hololive after all.
こうやって飲んじゃうからね。
We'll be drinking like this.
バンザーイ！
Banzai!
アキロゼ先輩おちょこあるのに、瓶から直接いってさ。ここ愛でさ。
Akirose-senpai, you have a cup but you're drinking straight from the bottle!
おちょこ使わないスタイル。
This is the "no cup" style.
途中からこっちになっちゃうね、どうしても。
Eventually, it just turns into this.
あついしね、ちょっとちっちゃいもんね。足んない足んない。
It's hot, and the cup is too small. Not enough!
こうやって酒瓶を持ってる姿って、なかなかなやっぱ見れないと思うから
Seeing us with these big bottles is quite rare...
お写真とかね、撮っちゃおうか。記念撮影。いいね！
...so maybe we should take some photos? A commemorative shot.
いいね、よしよし。何撮ろうかな？
Nice! What pose should we do?
まずはね、こう。乾杯。
First, let's toast.
満面の笑み。イエーイ！
Smiles everyone! Yay!
撮れた撮れた。
Did you get it?
いっぱい撮って、あのハッシュタグで呟いてください。
Take lots of photos and tweet them with the hashtag.
じゃあちょっと座ったりもしてみる？ いいね。
Shall we try sitting down too?
よし。よいしょ。
Nice.
ふぅ。よいしょ。
Phew.
乾杯！
Cheers!
お二人さん、なんかしたいポーズとかあります？
Do you two have any other poses you want to do?
したいポーズか。どうしようかな。
Another pose? What should we do?
ポーズじゃないんだけど、一列に並んで...
It's not a pose, but let's line up...
これ！ おちょこが回ってる！
Like this? The cup is spinning!
ノエルちゃん先頭にしてさ。
Let's have Noel-chan in front.
いいよ。ラミィちゃんも入ってもらって。
Okay. Lamy-chan, get in there too.
ノエルちゃんから... こうだね。
From Noel-chan... like this.
わー！ 酒飲み組でー！
Wow! The sake-drinking group!
これ合ってる？
Is this right?
いい感じ。止まってポーズ。
I think it's looking good! Let's pose.
どこだ？ こっちだな。こう？
Where is it? Like this?
ストップ！ こうか。
Stop! Like this.
はい。ありがとうございました。
Okay, thank you!
団長先頭なのにね、ちょっと見えてなかったからね。
Even though I'm in front, I couldn't see anything!
助かります。
That helps.
ラミィちゃんは？
What about Lamy-chan?
ラミィはやっぱりちょっと、最後に寝たやつ。
I want to do that "passed out" one at the end.
ちょっとね、引き気味とかね、撮れたらいいななんて思うんですけど。
A zoomed-out shot would be good.
じゃあちょっとあれだね。みんなで酔い潰れて。
Then let's all pretend to be drunk and passed out.
飲みすぎた、公園の真ん中で。
We drank too much in the middle of the park.
美味しかったな、今日のお酒。
That was great sake today.
最高だ。いっぱい飲もう。
It's the best. Let's drink more...
夢の中でも飲もう。うまいな。
I'll drink even in my dreams. So good.
身体によく染み込むよ、このポーズだったら。
This pose really helps it soak in.
なんか眠くなってきたね。おやすみなさい。
I'm getting sleepy. Good night.
寝るか。
Shall we sleep?
みんな、ありがとう。おやすみ。夢の中でライブ続きます。
Thank you everyone, good night. The live continues in our dreams.
あらゆる困難が科学で解決するこの平成の時代。
Any problem can be solved with science in this Heisei era.
人々の閉ざされた心の闇に蔓延る魑魅魍魎が存在していた。
But monsters still exist in the darkness of people's closed hearts.
科学の力ではどうしようもできない。その奇怪な輩に立ち向かう...
There is a man who stands against these mysterious creatures that science cannot handle.
神妙不可思議にて、胡散臭い男が一人。
A mysterious and suspicious man.
その名は、阿倍のコマソ。人は彼を、陰陽師と呼ぶ！
His name is... Abe no Komaso. People call him... Onmyoji!
悪霊退散！ 悪霊退散！
Evil spirits, begone! Evil spirits, begone!
怨霊、物の怪、困った時は...
When you're in trouble with spirits or monsters...
ドーマン！ セーマン！ ドーマン！ セーマン！
Doman! Seman! Doman! Seman!
すぐに呼びましょう。陰陽師、レッツゴー！
Call for the Onmyoji right away! Let's go!
イエーイ！
Yay!
鎮める...
Settle...
この世に未練残す死は...
Those who die leaving regrets in this world...
魑魅魍魎となり果てぬ...
Will turn into monsters and demons...
その悪しき地を清めるが...
To purify that evil land...
陰陽の道。
Is the way of the Onmyou.
人の世に...
In the world of humans...
生まれし悪を...
The evil that was born...
闇に...
Into the darkness...
葬れよ...
Bury it...
悪霊退散！ 悪霊退散！
Exorcise the evil spirits! Exorcise the evil spirits!
妖怪あやかし困ったときは...
When you're in trouble with youkai or monsters...
ドーマン！ セーマン！ ドーマン！ セーマン！
Douman! Seiman! Douman! Seiman!
助けてもらおう、陰陽師レッツゴー！
Let's get help, Onmyouji Let's Go!
生きながら...
While living...
怨み憎しみ募りしは...
Accumulating resentment and hatred...
悪鬼悪霊呼び覚ます...
Wakens evil ogres and spirits...
その激昂をなだめるも...
To soothe that wrath...
陰陽の道。
Is the way of the Onmyou.
愛しさの...
Of dear ones...
息づく果てに...
At the end of their breath...
病む心...
A diseased heart...
慰めよ...
Comfort it...
悪霊退散！ 悪霊退散！
Exorcise the evil spirits! Exorcise the evil spirits!
怨念怨恨困ったときは...
When you're in trouble with grudges and resentment...
ドーマン！ セーマン！ ドーマン！ セーマン！
Douman! Seiman! Douman! Seiman!
鎮めてもらおう、陰陽師レッツゴー！
Let's have them calmed down, Onmyouji Let's Go!
辛い時...
When it's painful...
楽しい時...
When it's fun...
人はそんな時心に隙間に闇ができる。
At those times, people get a gap of darkness in their hearts.
その心の闇に魔物たちは容赦なく入り込んでくるのだ！
The monsters will enter that darkness of the heart without mercy!
だから、苦しくても挫けるな！
So, even if it's painful, don't give up!
落ち込むな！ くよくよするな！
Don't be depressed! Don't worry!
何事にも屈しない強靭な心こそ...
A strong heart that doesn't bend to anything...
最強の武器なのだから！
...is the strongest weapon!
恨みしさで...
With resentment...
揺らめく心...
A wavering heart...
狙うもの...
Those who aim...
打ち砕け...
Smash them...
悪霊退散！ 悪霊退散！
Exorcise the evil spirits! Exorcise the evil spirits!
超常現象困ったときは...
When you're in trouble with paranormal phenomena...
ドーマン！ セーマン！ ドーマン！ セーマン！
Douman! Seiman! Douman! Seiman!
払ってもらおう、陰陽師レッツゴー！
Let's have them purified, Onmyouji Let's Go!
悪霊退散！ 悪霊退散！
Exorcise the evil spirits! Exorcise the evil spirits!
呪い呪われ困ったときは...
When you're in trouble with curses...
ドーマン！ セーマン！ ドーマン！ セーマン！
Douman! Seiman! Douman! Seiman!
相談しましょう、陰陽師レッツゴー！
Let's consult them, Onmyouji Let's Go!
やっぱり頼れる、陰陽師レッツゴー！
As expected, we can rely on them, Onmyouji Let's Go!
みんなのヒーロー、陰陽師！
Everyone's hero, Onmyouji!
成仏しろよ！
Rest in peace!
わぁ〜い！ Check it out!
Yay! Check it out!
Check it out!
会長！ いえいいえ〜い！ 来てくれてありがとうございます！
Kaichou! Yay yay! Thank you for coming!
いえーい！ 最強の二人キチェ！
Yay! The strongest duo is here!
来ちゃったんですね〜。うわぁ〜
We're here, aren't we~. Wow~
このライブのボインボイン半端ない... ありがとうございます！
The boin-boin in this live is no joke... Thank you very much!
いや、でもこう並ぶと実はアレなんだよね。
Well, but standing side-by-side like this is actually...
二人きりで並ぶの初めてなんだよね。
...the first time we've stood side-by-side just the two of us.
初めてなんですね。ちょっと緊張してます。
It's our first time, isn't it? I'm a bit nervous.
緊張してます。クパッ！
I'm nervous. Kupa!
クパッ？いや、でも高いんですね、身長やっぱり。会長威厳があるだ。
Kupa? But you really are tall, after all. You've got quite the presence, President.
ちょっとためこう…威厳をね。
Let's try a cool pose... with presence.
団長も威厳を。あ、威厳ですね！
I'll show some too. Ah, that's presence!
それは威厳ですね。団長、会長、まさかこんな所に呼んでいただけるなんて、ありがとうございます！
That's definitely presence. Danchou, Kaichou, thank you so much for inviting me to a place like this!
いえいえいえ。だって約束したじゃん。
No, no, no. I mean, we made a promise, right?
覚えてる？覚えてる？
Remember? Remember?
あ、あの、もう…あれですよね。龍園の。歌枠ね。あの、伸び代組の。
Ah, that... right. In the dragon's... singing stream. The 'Growth Group' one.
伸び代組ですからね、私たち。いや、伸び代の時に、あん時に歌えなかった曲があったんだよね。
We are the 'Growth Group', after all. Yeah, back when we did 'Growth', there was a song we couldn't sing.
それが今回歌った『Let's Go! Oh-my-way!!!』イェーイ！
And that's the one we sang this time, 'Let's Go! Oh-my-way!!!' Yay!
やりたかったんですよ、団長と。いや、でもやっぱり3Dでね、やりたいからさ。本当に良かった、今日。
I've been wanting to do it with you, Danchou. But I really wanted to do it in 3D, you know? It was so good today.
ウエーイ！イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
いや、めっちゃ楽しかったっす。本当ありがとうございます。
Yeah, it was super fun. Thank you so much.
いえいえいえ。でもあれだね。ちょっと…まあ、二人でこうやって並ぶのも最後になりますから。
No, no. But, you know, this will be the last time we stand side-by-side like this.
いっぱいに写真を撮ってくれたら嬉しいよ。ピッピッピッ。
I'd be happy if you take lots of photos. Beep-beep-beep.
伸び代、伸び代、伸び代コラボ。もう伸びちゃう。伸びちゃうの。ピョンピョンピョン。あ、ビョン！ボインボイン！
Growth, growth, growth collab. It's growing! Growing! Boing boing boing. Boing! Boing boing!
イェーイ！イェーイ！さて、ココ会長どれくらい…ちょっと動きをね、伝授したい。伝授してもらいたいな。
Yay! Yay! Now, Coco-kaichou, I want to learn some moves. I want you to teach me.
ちょっと団長いつもなんか…こういうポーズばっかしてるから。
Danchou only ever does this kind of pose.
マッスルポーズね。
The muscle pose, right.
マッスルポーズしかないから。
Since I only have muscle poses.
でもここからだもね、やっぱり腰の動き一つでセクシーになります。腰の動きか。なるほど。
But from here, just one hip movement makes you sexy. Hip movement? I see.
え、そう…何それ？
What... what's that?
腰をね。こうね、まずこう腰をね全体的に前にピ。前にピ。なるほどですね。ピ。
The hips. Like this, first push your hips forward like 'pi'. Forward 'pi'. I see. 'Pi'.
出してですね。ピ。
Push them out. 'Pi'.
ぐるっと横にね。
Then rotate them sideways.
あ、ぐるぐると。そうです。あ、なるほど。腰がボールか。これはいいです、会長っぽい。いいですね。
Ah, rotate. That's right. Ah, I see. Hips like a ball? This is good, very Kaichou-like. Nice.
そしてその動きをね…あ、でも伸び代ですね。ちょっと筋肉感ありすぎます。
And that movement... ah, but it's 'Growth'. It feels a bit too muscular.
ちょっとまだ…まだカクカクして。わざとカクカクしてます。
It's still... still a bit stiff. I'm being stiff on purpose.
え、これ違う？おじさんの初めてのエアロビクスじゃないですか。やめてくださいよ。
Wait, is this wrong? Isn't this like an old man's first aerobics class? Please stop!
いや、でも画面のみんなもね是非是非これやって、一緒に。え、こう？いや、難しいな。
But everyone watching, please try this too, together. Like this? Man, it's hard.
あ、でもいいっすよ。いいっすか？やった！伸び代です！伸び代イェーイ！
Ah, but it's good. It's good? Yay! It's 'Growth'! Growth yay!
え、でもちょっと待って。会長とさ…なんか…あれだな。先歌の時ピョンってして。
Wait, hold on. With Kaichou... during the song earlier, you went 'boing'.
ピョン、ピョン、ピョン。あーっ！ヒップの位置が全然違いすぎるんだよな。
Boing, boing, boing. Ah! Our hip levels are way too different.
またヒップが…ヒップがデカいもんね。失礼します。
Hips... your hips are big, after all. Excuse me.
そうですね。おーい！尻尾も付いてるんでね。ね、尻尾。尻尾だね。
That's right. Whoa! I've got a tail too, you know. Yeah, the tail. It's a tail.
あ、なんか団長…あれなんか記憶で。なんか…この尻尾…触ってもいい？
Ah, Danchou... for some reason, from memory... somehow... this tail... can I touch it?
あ、いいっすよ。全然いいっすよ。触って。
Ah, sure. It's totally fine. Touch it.
そわそわ。あ！ちょっと…チュチュチュ…あーっ！
Rustle rustle... Ah! Wait... *sound of being blown away* Ah!
ドラゴンの世界でも幸せになー！
Be happy in the dragon world too!
ワオワオワオワオワオワオワオ…あ、団長でした。
Wao wao wao wao wao wao wao... ah, it was Danchou.
ということで、皆さん！衣装チェンジしました！
So, everyone! I've changed my outfit!
ちょっとね、先ココ会長ぶんま…ぶん回しからね。ちょっと会長リ…リプレース…リスペクト。ちょっとリスペクトで、あれワオワオワオって入って来ました。
Since Kaichou just spun me around... I'm entering with 'wao wao wao' out of respect for her.
どうも団長です。どうどう？可愛いでしょ？結構ね、やっぱり最近…まあ3D配信団長の枠ではないけど、この前フレアとね歌ったりとかでこの衣装見覚えがあるんじゃないかなと思います。この衣装。
I'm Danchou. How is it? Cute, right? I think you might recognize this outfit from when I sang with Flare recently, even if it wasn't on my channel. This outfit.
団長ね、ほら…わ、わ、脇が…チュチュチュ…ちょっとそんなに近付かれると恥ずかしいなと思うんですが。ちょっと普段の服は結構…そうね、着物もそうだし、通常衣装もそうだし、私服も全部脇が見えないので、脇が見えるのはとても貴重です。
See... my a-a-armpits... wait, if you get that close, it's embarrassing. My usual clothes, like the kimono, regular outfit, and casual clothes, all hide the armpits. So seeing them is rare.
背中もちょっと見える。ぐるぐる…ね、見えます。おにそー…まあいつもおにそーなんでちょっと…
You can see my back too. Turn around... see, you can see it. Thigh-highs... well, they're always thigh-highs, so...
いっぱい写真撮って、あのハッシュタグでいっぱい呟いてくれると嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします。えーどうしようかな。なんか、せっかくだからアイドルっぽいポーズ。
Please take lots of photos and tweet them with the hashtag. Thank you. Now, what should I do? Since I'm here, maybe an idol-like pose.
なんかね先ワオワオワオとかさ…なんか先の曲が、もちろんねアイドル…あ、もう素晴らしいアイドルだったけど、二人ともね。
Earlier it was 'wao wao wao'... and the previous song was, of course, idol style... well, we were both wonderful idols.
ちょっと王道のアイドルじゃなかったなと思うから。ちょっとアイドルっぽ…あれこそ、あれか。この『見守り』。これね。記念の。
But I feel it wasn't exactly a mainstream idol style. So a bit of an idol... wait, that's it. This 'Mimamori' (Watching Over) pose. This anniversary one.
そう100万人記念突破…ん？突破した時の、あのサムネイルで
So, for the thumbnail from when I hit 1 million subs...
さ、これこれやろうかなって。
...I was thinking of doing that pose.
こんな感じか？
Was it something like this?
いや、いいんじゃないの？こういう感じ。
Yeah, this looks good. This kind of vibe.
指をこう、しかっけて。
Holding my finger up like this...
あ、カメラ、カメラマンさん、ありがとうございます！
Oh, cameraman! Thank you so much!
じゃあこういう感じで。
Alright, in this style...
チュッ！
*Wink*
団長158センチだからね。ちょっと小さいんだよな。
Danchou is 158cm tall, you see. I'm a bit small.
小さいから、団員さんの目線的には、もしかしてこれくらいになったりするのかな？
Because I'm small, from the perspective of a Danchou-in, maybe it looks like this?
いや、でも、団長の…あれかな？ちょっと団長の団員さん、あ、でも、あ。
Wait, but is it Danchou's... is it Danchou's Danchou-in? Ah, but...
坊やよしよし、あら、可愛いね。
There, there, good boy. Oh, how cute.
え、どうしたの？今日暇なの？
What's wrong? Are you free today?
あとからね、団長ライブ終わった後、
Later, after Danchou's live is over,
ちょっと、あの、一緒に遊ぼうか、っていうね。
let's play together for a bit!
これ、あの、大空警察に見られてると、ちょっと団長捕まっちゃうんで。
If the Oozora Police see this, Danchou will get arrested!
まあこういう色々写真撮って。あとは、フリフリとか。
Well, I've taken all sorts of photos. And also wiggling...
ルンルンルン。アイドル、アイドル。
*Humming* Idol, idol.
あ、でもせっかくだから、ココ会長…
Ah, but since I'm here, Coco Kaichou...
いや、なんか懐かしいね、ココ会長にそのポーズを、なんか伝授してもらった時があって。
This brings back memories. Coco Kaichou taught me a pose once.
そん時がすごいガニ股ポーズがめちゃくちゃ可愛い、
That bow-legged pose was incredibly cute.
アイドルとしてやっぱガニ股だよね、って言ってたから、ちょっとガニ股せっかくだからね。
She said, "For an idol, it's gotta be bow-legged!", so let me try it since I'm here.
ウィッ！
*Pose*
ちょっと普段の団長ではない感じのポーズもいいんじゃないかな。あと腰ね。
A pose that's a bit different from Danchou's usual style is nice too. Also, hips.
そうそう。腰付き、腰付きも教えてもらったから。
Right. Hip thrusts, she taught me hip thrusts too.
でもこの腰付きすると、なんか団長的に夢見る空思い出すんだよね。
But doing these hip thrusts reminds me of Yumemiru Sora.
トゥン、トゥン、トゥントゥントゥンって。
♪ Tun, tun, tun-tun-tun ♪
いや、そんな感じでお前いつ歌うんだよって思いましたか？
Anyway, were you thinking, "When are you going to sing?!"
団長もちろんこの衣装になったからには、アイドルソングを歌いたいと思います！
Danchou, of course, now that I'm in this outfit, I want to sing some idol songs!
いや、ちょっとこのアイドル衣装でね歌うのは、ま、みんなはね聞いたことあるし、
Well, singing in this idol outfit... I mean, everyone has heard me before,
団長が踊ってるのも見たことある感じなんですけど、
and you've seen Danchou dance,
この衣装ではね初めてなので、ぜひ聞いていってください。
but this is the first time in this outfit, so please listen!
では、いきます。
Alright, here we go!
ドキッ！こういうのが恋なの？
Dokki! Kouiu no ga Koi nano?
作詞・作曲 つんく
Lyrics/Composition: Tsunku
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
ねえ、歌うわ そうよ、あなたに
Hey, I'll sing. That's right, for you.
甘えたいけれど 恥ずかしいかもね
(かもね！ハイ！)
I want to be spoiled, but it might be embarrassing.
(Might be! Yes!)
願い事の呪文 ほら ムニャムニャムニャ
(ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！)
A spell for my wishes. Look, mumble mumble mumble.
(Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!)
ずっとこのまま 時が止まるかもね
(かもね！ハイ！)
Time might just stop like this forever.
(Might be! Yes!)
こういうのが恋なの ドキドキドキ
(ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！)
This is what love is. Heart thumping.
(Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!)
しかもね (かもね！ハイ！)
And besides. (Besides! Yes!)
スキスキスキ (ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！)
I love you, love you, love you. (Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!)
昨日よりもかもね
(かもね！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！アヤヤヤ…あ、間違えちゃった！)
Even more than yesterday, maybe.
(Maybe! Yes! Yes! Yes! Ayayaya... ah, I messed up!)
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ (ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！)
Hai! Hai! Hai! (Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!)
かもね！ (かもね！ハイ！)
Maybe! (Maybe! Yes!)
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ (ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！)
Hai! Hai! Hai! (Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!)
ねえ、歌って そうよ、あなたも
Hey, sing along. That's right, you too.
乙女の気持ちが伝わるといいな (いいな！ハイ！)
I hope a maiden's feelings reach you. (I hope! Yes!)
のどから出そうなくらい もうラブラブラブ
(ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！)
Like it's about to come out of my throat. Already love love love.
(Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!)
ずっとこのまま あなた素敵がいいな (いいな！ハイ！)
I hope you stay wonderful like this forever. (I hope! Yes!)
こういうのは初めて ドキドキドキ
(ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！)
This kind of love is a first. Heart thumping.
(Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!)
愛な (いいな！ハイ！)
It's love. (How nice! Yes!)
スキスキスキ (ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！)
I love you, love you, love you. (Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!)
さあ今日よりもいいな
(いいな！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！)
Now, even better than today.
(Better! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!)
ハロ／ハワユ
作詞・作曲 ナノウ
Hello/How Are You
Lyrics/Composition: Nanou
ハロ 窓を開けて 小さく呟いた
Hello, I opened the window and whispered softly
ハワユ 誰もいない 部屋で一人
How are you, all alone in an empty room
モーニ 朝が来たよ 土砂降りの朝が
Morning, morning has come, a morning with downpouring rain
ティックタック 私のネジを 誰か巻いて
Tick tock, someone please wind up my spring
ハロ 昔のアニメに そんなのいたっけな
Hello, was there someone like that in an old anime?
ハワユ 羨ましいな みんなに愛されて
How are you? I'm so jealous, you're loved by everyone.
スリーピィ 馬鹿なこと言ってないで 支度をしなくちゃ
Sleepy, stop talking nonsense and get ready.
クライ 涙の跡を隠すため
Cry, to hide the traces of my tears.
もう口癖になった「まぁいっか」 昨日の言葉がふと頭をよぎる
My favorite phrase "it's okay" now, yesterday's words suddenly cross my mind.
「もう君には全然期待してないから」
"I don't expect anything from you anymore."
そりゃまぁ私だって 自分に期待などしてないけれど
Well, even I don't expect anything from myself, but...
あれは一体どういうつもりですか
What on earth did you mean by that?
喉元まで出かかった言葉
Words that were on the tip of my tongue.
口をついて出たのは嘘
What came out of my mouth was a lie.
こうして今日も私は貴重な
In this way, today again, I'm
言葉を浪費して生きていく
living my life by wasting precious words.
なぜ隠してしまうのですか 笑われるのが怖いのですか
Why do you hide? Are you afraid of being laughed at?
誰にも会いたくないのですか それ本当ですか
Do you not want to see anyone? Is that really true?
曖昧という名の海に溺れて 息もできないほど苦しいの
Drowning in a sea named ambiguity, it's so painful I can't even breathe.
少し声が聞きたくなりました 本当に弱いな
I wanted to hear your voice a little bit. I'm really weak.
一向に進まない支度の途中 朦朧とした頭で思う
In the middle of getting ready, not progressing at all, I think with a hazy head.
「もう理由をつけて休んでしまおうかな」
"Maybe I should just make up an excuse and take a rest."
いやいや分かってますって 何となく言ってみただけだよ
No, no, I know. I just said it for no reason.
分かってるから怒らないでよ
I know, so don't get mad at me.
幸せだろうと不幸せだろうと
Whether you're happy or unhappy,
平等に残酷に朝日は昇る
the sun rises equally and cruelly.
生きていくだけで精一杯の私に
For me, who is doing my best just to live,
これ以上何を望むというの
what more do you expect from me?
なぜ気にしてしまうのですか 本当は愛されたいのですか
Why do you care? Do you actually want to be loved?
その手を離したのは誰ですか 気が付いていますか
Who was it that let go of that hand? Have you noticed?
人生にタイムカードがあるなら 終わりの時間はいつなんだろう
If life had a time card, when would the end time be?
私が生きた分の給料は 誰が払うんですか
Who pays the salary for the time I lived?
サンキュー ありがとうって言いたいの
Thank you. I want to say thank you,
サンキュー ありがとうって言いたいよ
Thank you. I want to say thank you.
サンキュー 一度だけでもいいから
Thank you. Even if it's just once,
心の底から大泣きしながら ありがとうって言いたいの
while crying my heart out from the bottom of my heart, I want to say thank you.
なぜ隠してしまうのですか 本当は聞いてほしいのですか
Why do you hide? Do you actually want someone to listen?
絶対に笑ったりしないから 話してみませんか
I'll never laugh, so why don't you try talking to me?
口を開かなければ分からない 思ってるだけでは伝わらない
If you don't open your mouth, I won't know. Just thinking it won't convey it.
なんて面倒くさい生き物でしょう 人間というのは
What troublesome creatures humans are.
ハロ ハワユ
Hello, how are you?
ハロ ハワユ あなたに
Hello, how are you? To you.
ハロ ハワユ
Hello, how are you?
はい！みんな、2曲連続で聴いていただきました！
Yes! Everyone, you've listened to two songs in a row!
いやぁ、どうでしたか？いや、みんなありがとう、来てくれて。
Well, how was it? Thank you all for coming.
あぁー、いやぁありがとうございます。
Ah, well, thank you very much.
いや、団長、ちょっと一人でね、こうやってアイドル衣装で歌うのも、やっぱちょっと普段と違う感じでいいかな？
Well, I thought it might be nice for Danchou to sing alone in this idol costume like this, it feels a bit different from usual?
いや、でもなんかちょっと一人だと、ちょっと寂しくなってきたな。「ハロ／ハワユ」もね、ちょっと儚げな歌だったし。
But, somehow, being alone makes me feel a bit lonely. "Hello/How Are You" was also a bit of a transient song.
え、ちょっと、寂しくなってきたなー。
Um, I'm getting a bit lonely...
んーー。
Hmm...
あれ、なんか団長の幻聴が聞こえてきたな。
Wait, I thought I heard some hallucinations of myself.
あ、それ、え、どっこい、どっこい、あ、えー、聞こ、頑張るね。
Oh, that... yo-ho, yo-ho... ah, eh, I hear it, I'll do my best.
ちょっと引っ込んできてね、わー、あ、そーれ、どっこい、どっこい、どっこい、どっこい、うわー！
Let me step back a bit... here we go! Yo-ho, yo-ho, yo-ho, yo-ho, whoa!
もう、じゃなくていいんじゃない？
Hey, isn't that enough?
いやいやいや、なんか抜擢すごいよかったよ、本当に。
No, no, no, the selection was really good, seriously.
でもさっきさ、ほら、ほら、リハーサルの時にさ、
But earlier, during the rehearsal,
ほら団長がね、『あ〜、歌った〜』ってなった時に、
when Noel was like "Ah~ I sang it~",
フレアが『う〜』みたいにちゃちゃ入れるって言ってたのに、
I said I'd tease her like "Ooh~",
ガチでさ、聴き入ってくれてたでしょ。
but you were actually listening so intently.
めっちゃ嬉しいんだけど。
I'm so happy.
ですごい可愛かったから、もうこの後ずっとソロでええんちゃうかと思って。
And it was so cute, I thought it'd be fine if you just went solo from here on.
いやいやそんなこと。
No, no, no.
今日はね、フレアがね、来てくれましたよ、みんな。じゃじゃーん。
Today, Flare has come for us, everyone! Ta-da!
どーもー。コメント見てるよ。
Hello! I'm watching the comments.
いつもノエルがお世話になってます。ありがとうございます。
Thank you for always taking care of Noel. Thank you very much.
え、どういう旦那さん？ 妻？ 今日どういう感じ、どういう感じ？
Wait, what's the vibe today? Husband? Wife? How are we doing this?
えー、じゃあ今日だけは、あの大将さんに、ま、旦那は譲るとして、
Hmm, well, for today only, I'll let the commander be the husband,
私は親友って形でいくよ。親友。
and I'll be the best friend. Best friend.
うわーなんか新鮮、新鮮。
Wow, that feels so fresh, fresh!
なんかちょっと、あれ、変わった、なんか違う、なんか扉が開きそう。びん。
It's a bit... different, like a new door is opening. *Ping*
じゃあ私たち、あの、二人、あの、一番仲の良い親友、あ、この後ちょっと出づらくなるかもしれない。
So we're... the two of us... the closest of best friends... ah, this might make it hard to go out later.
あ、それ言うとね、それ言うと確かに。
Ah, when you put it that way, true.
いやあ、来てくれてありがとう。
Well, thanks for coming.
じゃあさ、あれだね。ちょっとさ、何だっけ歌う？
So, it's that time. Shall we sing that one?
え、ネタ曲歌う？
Eh, are we singing a meme song?
え、ネタ曲、あ、あのレッツゴー陰陽師とかそういう。
Eh, a meme song? Like "Let's Go Onmyouji" or something?
今の流れだったらやっぱり、なんかネタ曲…
Given the current flow, maybe a meme song...
いや、フレアさん、我々歌った曲あるじゃないですか。
Wait, Flare-san, we have a song we've sung together, right?
なんか歌ったっけ？
Did we sing something?
歌った、歌った、思い出して。
We did, we did! Remember!
え、なんか歌ったっけ？
Eh, did we?
ということで、聴いてください。いい？ いくよ。
So, please listen. Ready? Here we go.
じゃあみんな、まあわかると思うけど。聴いてください。
Everyone probably knows this one. Please listen to...
ナイショの話。
..."Naisho no Hanashi".
One, two!
One, two, three, four!
ナイショの話
作詞・作曲/ryo
Naisho no Hanashi
Lyrics/Composition: ryo
今日も元気な目覚ましが
Today again, a cheerful alarm
私の脳に朝を告げる
tells my brain that morning has come
寝ぼけ眼こすったら
When I rub my sleepy eyes,
一日が始まるわ
the day begins
机の上に置いたまま
Left on top of the desk,
忘れ物を今日もまたしてる
I've forgotten something again today
全力疾走で追いかけた
I chased after it at full speed,
どうして気が付かないかな
why don't you notice?
ずっと私、このまま、
Don't think I'll be like this
いるなんて思わないでよ
forever
きっといつかどこかの誰かが、私のこと
I'm sure someday, someone somewhere...
もらってしまうのわかってるの？
...will take me away, do you realize that?
その時になったって遅いんだから
It'll be too late by then,
その時になったって泣いたって知らないんだから
and I won't care even if you cry by then
そんな顔をしたってダメなんだから
Making that face won't work,
やはり、そう、ちょっぴりドキッとした
after all, yeah, I was a little startled
じゃない、はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Not really! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
さっきからあの制服の子が、気になっての、
You've been interested in that girl in the uniform
バレバレだわ
for a while now, it's so obvious
私が隣にいるのに、
Even though I'm right next to you,
それってどういうつもりなの
what do you think you're doing?
何も言わないでいいから、
You don't have to say anything,
私のことを一番に
just make me your number one
大事にしてよ
Treat me with care
なのにあなたはいつだってそうやって、
And yet you're always like that,
鈍感なのわかってるの
do you know how insensitive you are?
今さら気づいたって遅いんだから
It's too late to notice now,
今さら言い訳したって知らないんだから
and I won't care even if you make excuses now
そんな顔をしたってダメなんだから
Making that face won't work,
やはり、言う、ちょっぴり怒りたくもなるわ
after all, I'll say it, it makes me want to get a little angry
ゆうの！ はい！ はい！ はい！
I'm telling you! Hai! Hai! Hai!
その時になるまで 見ていてよね
Keep watching me until that time comes
その時になったら 泣いちゃうかもね
I might end up crying when that time comes
そんな顔しちゃったら ダメかもですね
It might be bad if I make a face like that
リアルになっちゃうけど ナイショの話
It's becoming real, but it's a secret story
その時になったって 遅いんだから
Because it'll be too late when that time comes
その時に泣いたって 知らないんだから
Because I won't care if you cry then
そんな顔したって ダメなんだから
Because making a face like that won't work
でもね いつも サンキューって思ってたり...
But you know, I'm always thinking "thank you"...
して！
...and all!
ねぇ、ふーちゃんとこの曲歌えてすっごく嬉しい
Hey, I'm so happy I could sing this song with Fuu-chan.
やっとね！ずっと歌いたかったよね
Finally! We've always wanted to sing it.
嬉しい！3Dで歌いたかった
I'm so happy! I wanted to sing it in 3D.
大好きだよ〜
I love you~
はい！ハッピーハート作っちゃって！大好きだよ、船長も！
Alright! Making a happy heart! I love you too, says the Captain!
うわぁ！びっくりした！
Whoa! You scared me!
いつからいたの！？
How long have you been there!?
え、今ここにハートから生まれました。二人の子供だよ。大事に育ててにょ。
Oh, I was just born from the heart right here. I'm your child. Take good care of me, okay?
ちょっときついね。ちょっと配置戻っていい？
That's a bit much. Can we go back to our positions?
戻るな戻るな！なんで来たと思う？
Don't go back! Why do you think I came?
え、なんで来てくれたの？
Oh, why did you come?
ノエルさんの100万人だから決まってるでしょ！
Because it's Noel-san's 1 million celebration, obviously!
えー、嬉しい！ありがとう、マリンちゃん！
Oh, I'm so happy! Thank you, Marine-chan!
喧嘩しないで！私を巡って争わないで！
Don't fight! Don't fight over me!
してない、してない
We're not, we're not.
本当にありがとう。マリンもね、今日来てくれました。ありがとう！
Thank you so much. Marine also came today. Thank you!
来たよ〜。ちょっときついね。来たよ〜。
I'm here~. It's a bit cramped. I'm here~.
なんで私の時だけ「きつい」って言うの？嘘！帰ろうかな！
Why do you only say "it's cramped" when I'm here? No way! Maybe I should go home!
え、帰んないで帰んないで！
Hey, don't go, don't go!
せっかく3人揃ったからにはさ、写真撮影とかしたくないっすか？
Since the three of us are together, don't you want to take some photos?
えー、どうしようかなぁ〜
Hmm, what should we do~
なんで！？なんでこのノリは！
Why!? Why this reaction!
でもしたいね。
But I do want to.
あ、でもあれかな？その前に、今日歌だから...
Oh, but maybe... before that, since today is about singing...
写真撮影の前に、歌？
Singing before the photo shoot?
気になっちゃう感じですか？
Are you curious about it?
どんなネタ歌？
What kind of joke song?
ネタじゃないから！やめて、そういうキャラじゃないんだけど私！
It's not a joke song! Stop it, that's not my character!
あ、なんかコメントで、トレンド云々とか書いてた気がしたけど、見えてなかった？気のせい？
Oh, in the comments, I thought I saw something about trends, did you see it? Or was it just my imagination?
どれどれ？
Where, where?
一番動体視力の高い私に任せてください。
Leave it to me, I have the best dynamic visual acuity.
お、2位か？お、2位！やったー！3位じゃない、2位だよ！
Oh, #2? Oh, #2! Yay! Not #3, it's #2!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
でもすげーな、トレンド1位がでかすぎたか。
But that's amazing. Was the #1 spot too big?
2位でもすごく嬉しいです。ありがとう！
We're so happy even with #2. Thank you!
じゃあちょっと、3人揃ったからには、どうしても歌いたい曲があって。
So, since the three of us are here, there's a song I really want to sing.
あの、3期生と言ったら、まずデビューした時、歌枠、必ず歌った曲、あったの覚えてる？
You know, speaking of 3rd Gen, remember the song we always sang in our singing streams when we first debuted?
え、何それ？
Eh, what's that?
出しちゃって！覚えてるよ！
Come on! I remember it!
船長、覚えてる？え、嘘でしょ！？お前も覚えてる？
Does the Captain remember? What, seriously!? Do you remember too?
めっちゃ歌ってたじゃん！あれ、あれね。
We sang it all the time! That one, you know.
コメントでもね、分かってると思うけど。
I think the comments know too.
ノエルがぴーぴー泣いてたやつね。
The one where Noel was crying like a baby.
誕生日ね、ちょっとそれは置いといて。
On your birthday? Let's put that aside for a moment.
3人で歌いたい曲があるの。皆さん聴いてください。
There's a song I want to sing with the three of us. Everyone, please listen.
それでは歌いたいと思います。よし、いいっすか？
So, we're going to sing. Alright, ready?
それでは聴いてください。「風になる」。
Please listen. "Becoming the Wind".
風になる
Kaze ni Naru
目を閉じて 取り戻せ 恋の歌
Close your eyes and bring back the song of love
青空に隠れている 手を伸ばしてもう一度
It's hidden in the blue sky, reach out your hand once more
忘れないで すぐそばに 僕がいる いつの日も
Don't forget, I'm right by your side, every single day
星空を眺めている 一人きりの夜明けも
Gazing at the starry sky, even in the dawn when you're alone
たった一つの心 悲しみにくれないで
With just one heart, please don't give in to sadness
君のため息なんて 春風に変えてやる
I'll turn even your sighs into a spring breeze
陽のあたる坂道を 自転車で駆けのぼる
Cycling up the sun-drenched hill
君と失くした思い出 乗せてゆくよ
Carrying the memories I lost with you
ラララララ 口ずさむ くちびるを染めてゆく
La-la-la... humming along, painting my lips
君と見つけた幸せ 花のように
The happiness I found with you is like a flower
忘れていた窓開けて 走り出せ 恋の歌
Open the forgotten window and start running, song of love
青空に隠れている 手をかざしてもう一度
It's hidden in the blue sky, shield your eyes and look once more
忘れないよ すぐそばに 君がいる いつの日も
I won't forget, you're right by my side, every single day
星空に輝いてる 涙揺れる明日も
Shining in the starry sky, even in the tomorrow where tears tremble
たった一つの言葉 この胸に抱きしめて
Just one word, I'll hold it close to my heart
君のため僕は今 春風に吹かれてる
For you, I'm now being blown by the spring breeze
陽のあたる坂道を 自転車で駆けのぼる
Cycling up the sun-drenched hill
君と誓った約束 乗せてゆくよ
Carrying the promise I made to you
ラララララ 口ずさむ くちびるを染めてゆく
La-la-la... humming along, painting my lips
君と出会えた幸せ 祈るように
The happiness of meeting you is like a prayer
楽しいな、ねぇ
It's so much fun, isn't it?
楽しかったー！
That was so much fun!
もうずっとここにいよう
Let's just stay here forever.
おれ、どうしたの？ 帰るよ、マリン
Wait, what's wrong with me? Let's go home, Marine.
えっ、待ってノエルのステージだから
Eh, wait, this is Noel's stage!
いや、待って待って待って
No, wait, wait, wait.
写真撮ろうよ！
Let's take a photo!
あ、忘れてた
Ah, I forgot.
帰ろうとしてたわ
I was just about to head home.
ねぇ、忘れないでよー
Hey, don't forget that!
みんなすごい拍手だよ
Everyone's giving such a huge round of applause.
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ちょっと三人でさ、せっかくねアイドル衣装だから、ちょっと写真撮りたいなーって
I was thinking, since the three of us are finally in our idol outfits, I'd like to take some photos together.
え、どんな写真撮る？おっぱいの大きさでも比べる？
Oh, what kind of photos? Should we compare our breast sizes?
いいよ、比べたいならいいけど
Sure, I don't mind if you want to.
あ、そんななめるように
Ah, staring at me like that...
あ、マリンいい匂い
Ah, Marine smells nice.
恥ずかしいね こういうのね
It's embarrassing, seeing ourselves like this.
あんまり見ないからね
Because we don't see it often.
ふーちゃん 見て
Fu-chan, look!
ふーちゃん見て 見て！
Fu-chan, look, look!
見え... えー！ 見えてる！ 見えてる！
I can see... Whoa! I can see it! I can see it!
今日はよう持っておる
You've got a lot there today.
持ってるね！ 今日パット入ってるの？
She does! Are you wearing pads today?
入ってないよ！
I'm not!
嘘つけ！
Liar!
入れてないよね！？ マリンおけーっしょ！？
I didn't! Marine, you agree, right?!
はい！ おけー！
Yes! Okay!
じゃあ ちょっとあれかな？
Well then, maybe we should...?
あ、もう もしかして
Oh, perhaps...
あともうちょっと撮れるって
They say we can take a few more photos.
本当？
Really?
もうちょっと撮れる？ じゃあどうしようかな 何撮ろうかな
A few more? Then what should we do? What should we take?
折角だから... じゃあ２ポーズ撮れるって！
Since we're here... they say we can take two poses!
２ポーズ！ 何がいい？
Two poses! What would be good?
コメント... じゃあ１ポーズは私たち決めよう
The comments... Let's decide one pose ourselves.
うんと... どうしようかな
Hmm... What should it be?
いいの？ それで任せて 本当に
Is that okay? Are you really leaving it to us?
あ、じゃあ やっぱりコメントでも拾いたいかな
Ah, well, I guess I'd like to take one from the comments too.
コメント見てる コメント見てる！
I'm looking at the comments! Looking at the comments!
コメント見てるポーズ
A "reading comments" pose.
なるほど 船長頭大きい え？
I see. "Sencho's head is big"... Wait, what?
ちょっとこの辺に立とうかな
Maybe I'll stand around here.
イエーイ 小顔！
Yay! Small face!
なんか等身が！
The proportions!
女特有の！
The typical girl thing!
だっちゅーのする？
Should we do "Datchu-no"?
いいよ お姉さんだもんね だっちゅーの！
Sure! We're big sisters after all. Datchu-no!
なんか... なんかフレアかっこいい！
Flare... Flare looks cool somehow!
断末魔になっちゃった
It turned into a death rattle.
フレアかわいい！
Flare is so cute!
断末魔になっちゃったから 真ん中どうぞ
It turned into a death rattle, so please take the center.
あ、ありがとう！
Oh, thank you!
ちょっ... おいおい おいおい 前被ってるじゃん！
Hey... Whoa, whoa, whoa! You're blocking the front!
いや 本当ありがとう二人とも
Seriously, thank you both so much.
まだここにいる
I'm still here.
入るよ 入るよ
We're going in, we're going in.
マリン 出てこないで 帰ろ！ ほらっ
Marine, don't come out. Let's go home! Come on.
いや ちょっと！ なんで手て... なんで なんで！
Wait, hey! Why holding hands... Why, why!
じゃな！ あとから あとからね！
See ya! Later, okay, later!
あとからよろしくお願いします
See you later.
いや なんかちょっと二人でてぇてぇする前に...
Well, before those two get all lovey-dovey...
団長はね あの団員さん 本当今日は
I... to all the knights, really, today...
100万人記念3Dライブ 見てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for watching the 1 million subscriber 3D live!
団長からね 実は あの ちょっとね お知らせがあるんですけど
I actually have a small announcement to make.
いいですか？ ちょっとね お知らせ
Is that okay? An announcement.
いや 本当に団長ね この度 なんと みんなびっくりすると思うんだけど
I... this time, well, I think everyone will be surprised.
まあ 白銀ノエル100万人記念ということで 今回
To celebrate Shirogane Noel reaching 1 million subscribers, this time...
なな なんと グ グッズをだ グ グッズを出しまっ...
I'm... I'm releasing g- goods... G- goods...
出しましたー！
I've released them!
イエーイ！
Yay!
白銀ノエル 100万人記念 6月26日 販売開始
記念グッズ全部セット
Shirogane Noel 1M Commemoration. Sales start June 26th.
Commemorative Goods Full Set
あ、すいません なんかすごい 天の声が聞こえる気がする
Ah, excuse me. I feel like I'm hearing voices from heaven.
はい！ なんと100万人記念ということで グッズを出させていただきました！
Yes! To celebrate 1 million subscribers, I've released commemorative goods!
手紙もらえるの？
We get a letter?
そう そうなんですよ ちょっと 手紙もあるんですけど
Yes, that's right. There's a letter too.
一個一個ね ちょっと紹介させていただきたいと思います！
I'd like to introduce each item one by one!
じゃあ ちょっと運営さん いいですか？
Management, could you put them up?
わたお先生描き下ろしB2タペストリー
B2 Tapestry illustrated by Wata-sensei
よし！ で、まず一つ目！ この わたお先生 団長のね 父上の
Alright! First up! This one, by Wata-sensei, my creator...
描き下ろしのB2タペストリー！ これさ
...an original B2 tapestry! Look at this.
見ての通り なんと3期生に団長祝われてるんですよ
As you can see, the 3rd Gen members are celebrating with me.
ねえ！ 祝われてるんですよ！
Right! They're celebrating me!
ねえ！ さっきね ちょっと まあ マリンとかフレアも言ってたけど
See? Marine and Flare were saying it earlier, too.
なんかね ちょっと大人っぽいよね マリフレ大人っぽくて
They look a bit mature, don't they? Mari-Flare look mature.
あの ぺこるしがね ちょっと幼い感じで なんかね
And Peko-Rushi have this young feel to them.
すごい可愛い感じになってます！ はい！
It's a really cute illustration! Yes!
いや 本当に ぜひぜひこちらゲットしてみてください！
So please, definitely check this out!
で、次行きます！ ぽいっ！
Next one! Pop!
100万人記念アクリルミラーパネル
1M Commemorative Acrylic Mirror Panel
で、こちらが100万人記念アクリルミラーパネルです！
This is the 1 million subscriber commemorative acrylic mirror panel!
なるほど その発想なかったわ これエジソン
I see. I didn't think of that. This is Edison-level.
そう こちらはね ま、どういうことかっていうと
Well, as for what this is...
ま、団長ね 金盾届いたんですけど ちょっと部屋がね
I received my Gold Play Button, but my room is...
ちょっと汚くて まだ金盾みんなに写真ちょっと載せられてないんだけどね
It's a bit messy, so I haven't been able to post a photo for everyone yet.
金盾届いて やっぱりね 団長だけでなくて
Since I got the Gold Play Button, I thought, not just for me...
あの団員さんにも やっぱ金盾っぽい そういうさ
I wanted the knights to have something like a Gold Play Button too.
100万人っていう その証というのをね やっぱり一緒に飾りたいなと思って
A proof of 1 million subscribers that we can display together.
あの こちらアクリルミラーパネル はい 発売しました！
So, we've released this acrylic mirror panel!
なんかすごい天の声が聞こえるけど でも褒められてる気がする ありがとうございます
I keep hearing voices from heaven, but I feel like I'm being praised. Thank you.
では次行きますか！ ぽいっ！
Shall we move on to the next one? Pop!
100万人記念Tシャツ 白 or 黒
1M Commemorative T-Shirt White or Black
で、こちら！ こちらね あの 朝活配信でもちょっとアンケートをとったんだけど
And this! For this one, I actually did a poll during a morning stream.
オタクなのバレないのどっち！？ 白？ 黒？
Which one won't out me as an otaku? White? Black?
えー、すごい！ なんか黒ちょっとギャル男だなぁ！
Wow! The black one looks a bit like something a "gyaru-o" would wear!
さあ、なんと 100万人記念Tシャツって ちょっと静かにしててね！？
Well, this is the 1 million commemorative T-shirt... Hey, quiet down for a second!
ちょっと静かにしててね！？ 今団長喋ってるからね！
Keep it down! I'm talking right now!
そう 初めてのTシャツを 出しました！
Yes, I've released my very first T-shirt!
いや すごいカッコいいでしょ！ ま、さっきのね 天の声も言ってたんだけど
Isn't it cool? Like the voices from heaven were saying earlier...
団長らしく その白銀聖騎士団の紋章を あの 何て言うんだろうな
In my style, it has the Shirogane Order of Knights emblem, like...
ま、バァンって載せつつ ま、なんか普段使いもできるようなカッコいい感じになってます！
BAM! It's right there, but it's also a cool design for everyday use!
白と黒で あの二色展開あるんですけど 今回
It comes in two colors, white and black.
あの さっきも出たように 全部セットがあるんですけど
And as mentioned before, there's a full set available.
全部セットを買ったら その団長のお手紙もつくんですが そこで注意点が
If you buy the full set, you get my letter, but there's a point of caution.
あの 白と黒 二種類あるので あの 購入される方は
Since there are two colors, white and black, for those purchasing...
あの 間違いなくよろしくお願いします！
Please make sure you choose the right one!
なんならば 二色とも買ってくれると 嬉しいです！ よろしくお願いします！
Better yet, I'd be happy if you bought both colors! Thank you!
いや 本当にね すごいオシャレな感じになってるんですよ
Seriously, it's turned out looking really stylish.
いや みんな白と黒 どっちも買ってください 本当ね 団長サンプルいただいたというか サンプル見たんですけど
So everyone, please buy both white and black. I received samples... or rather, I saw them.
...ね、どっちもね
...neither of them...
いい感じにかっちょいい感じでね、そう
They've got a nice, cool feel to them, yeah.
ギャルを？ちょっと天の声なんて言ったか忘れたんだけど
A gyaru? I forgot what the voice from above said, but...
ギャル男でも着れる、ま、とにかく、ちょっとカッコいい感じになってるので
Even a 'gyaru-o' can wear it. Anyway, it has a bit of a cool vibe,
ぜひぜひ着てくれると嬉しいです！
so I'd be really happy if you'd wear it!
いや、本当に皆にこの、ま、本当ね、ずっと前から
Honestly, to everyone, this... well, for a really long time,
ずっとこれをね、計画してて、やっとお知らせできたのがすごく嬉しいです。
we've been planning this, and I'm so glad I could finally announce it.
このあと22時、22時から発売されるので、よろしくお願いいたします！
It will be on sale from 10 PM tonight, so please check it out!
いやぁ、じゃあちょっと団長ね、まあここで最後の曲になってしまうんですが、
Well then, it's already time for the final song from your Captain,
あの皆さまに、騎士さんに感謝の気持ちを込めて、アイドルらしいノエルちゃんを最後に見せたいと思います。
but I want to show you one last idol-like Noel, filled with gratitude for all the Knights.
それでは感謝の気持ちを込めて歌わせていただきます。それでは聴いてください、「ファンサ」。
And so, I'll sing with all my heart. Please listen: 'Fan-sa'.
好きになって　もっと
Please love me more
私を見て　もっと
Please look at me more
恩返しは　愛のこもった投げキッスで
My way of repaying you is with a love-filled blown kiss
気のせいじゃない　目が合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting
ハート作って　恋しちゃってください！
Make a heart shape and fall in love with me!
やれること　何でもします　NGなしで　体当たり挑戦
I'll do anything I can, no restrictions, I'll give it my all
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ　「ふざけんな！」誰より分かってるし
The hater comments I found, 'Don't give me that!' I know better than anyone
でも大丈夫　ここに立てば　みんながいる　行くよ！
But it's okay, when I stand here, you're all with me. Let's go!
好きになって　もっと
Please love me more
私を見て　もっと
Please look at me more
恩返しは　愛のこもった投げキッスで
My way of repaying you is with a love-filled blown kiss
虜にする　もっと
I'll captivate you more
夢を見せる　もっと
I'll show you dreams more
楽しんでって　愛のこもったスペシャルな日と
Please enjoy this special, love-filled day
ファンサしちゃうぞ！
I'm gonna give you some fan service!
お手紙も書いてください　何度も読んで　宝物にします
Please write letters to me too, I'll treasure them forever
スキャンダル　まだ早いけど　裏切りません　宣言しときます
Scandals are still far off, but I promise I won't betray you
嫉妬嫌がらせには負けない　「ふざけんな！」実力で勝ってやる
I won't lose to jealousy, 'Don't give me that!' I'll win with skill
だから辞めない　負けず嫌いな　私はいる　行くよ！
I won't quit, because I'm a sore loser. Let's go!
拳上げて　もっと
Raise your fists more
汗をかいて　もっと
Sweat even more
恩返しは　愛のこもったノエビームで
My way of repaying you is with a love-filled Noe-beam
大歓声　もっと
Big cheers, even more
まだまだだね　もっと
Not enough yet, more
受け止めてね　愛のこもったわがままソング
Please accept it, this love-filled, selfish song
ファンサしちゃうぞ！
I'm gonna give you some fan service!
終わりが近づく
The end is drawing near
寂しいね　楽しいのに
It's lonely, even though it's fun
泣きそうだよ
I feel like I'm going to cry
次も次も　また会えるよね　約束！
Next time, and the time after, we'll meet again, right? Promise!
優しさに溢れている言葉も　心無い誰かの言葉さえも
Both words overflowing with kindness, and heartless words too...
必要なんだ　必要なんだ　強くなろう
They're both necessary, so I'll become stronger
好きに叫べ　もっと
Shout as much as you like, more
楽しんじゃえ　もっと
Just have fun, more
忘れないで　特別な日になりますように
Don't forget, I hope this becomes a special day
共に歌おう　ずっと
Let's sing together, always
共に歩もう　ずっと
Let's walk together, always
合言葉は　とびっきりの「L・O・V・E」
Our password is a super special 'L-O-V-E'
好きになって　もっと
Please love me more
私を見て　もっと
Please look at me more
恩返しは　愛のこもった投げキッスで
My way of repaying you is with a love-filled blown kiss
虜にする　もっと
I'll captivate you more
夢を見せる　もっと
I'll show you dreams more
楽しんでって　愛のこもったスペシャルな日と
Please enjoy this special, love-filled day
ファンサしちゃうぞ！
I'm gonna give you some fan service!
大好きー！
I love you!
皆さん、今日は本当にありがとうございましたー！
Everyone, thank you so much for today!
白銀ノエルでした！バイバーイ！
This was Shirogane Noel! Bye-bye!